RICARDO ALBERTO PÉREZ CANDELAS

me@ricardoperezcandelas.com 5568583198 https://ricardoperezcandelas.com/

Site Reliability Engineer, Full-stack software developer with 5+ years industry experience specializing in back-end development and devops. Born and raised in Texcoco, Mexico State, I enjoy playing and following college football and flag football, amateur guitar and drums player, mindfull and successfull books.

</> </> SKILLS

WEB JAVASCRIPT HTML 5 CSS MVC REST

IAVASCRIPT NODE. JS JQUERY BOOTSTRAP REACT. JS BACKBONE. JS REACT NATIVE

DATABASE MYSQL POSTGRESQL NOSQL ORM

AWS DIGITALOCEAN DOCKER DOCKER COMPOSE CI/CD JENKINS GITLAB BITBUCKET GCP **DEVOPS**

KUBERNETES MAKISU PROJECT HELM HARNESS JENKINS PIPELINES TERRAFORM

BACKEND **REST ISON API DESIGN PATTERNS TDD**

PROJECT AGILE GITHUB TEAMWORK LEADER GITFLOW GITHUB FLOW

EMPLOYMENT

Site Reliability Engineer II,

Wizeline

Making and follow DevOps practices and culture

- Work with internationa team remotly
- First one DevOpsDays in Mexico 2020 core-organizer
- Contribute to internal projects
- Estudy GCP and AWS proffessional certifications
- DevOps practitioner

Docker Kubernetes DevOps Terraform AWS GCP Organizer SCRUM Jenkins Harness Gitlab Ruby Bash Groovy

Team Leader, Nimanic

2018-03 — 2019-09

2019-09 — Present

Software Team Leader Engineer and Cloud Operator

- Learn internet of things protocols and communication
- Start with Agile practices
- Learn startup cycle and releases
- Start implementation of continuous delivery and deployment
- Migration of all production environment from Heroku to AWS
- Implement high availability

Ruby MQTT Lead Heroku AWS Telematics Jenkins SCRUM React Native PHP AWS Node, js React. JS Redux Workflow CI/CD

Team Leader, Mellow

2017-09 — 2018-03

Consulting

Tech Team leader at Mellow Consulting, leading an 8 people team

- Lead a tech team of 8 people
- Implement workflows and process for development
- Talk with clients to create products
- Plan, propose and implement digital solutions for client requirements with designers and marketing teams
- Teach and propose solutions to developer team
- Apply agile techniques for meets and project teams

Agile Lead SCRUM React Native PHP AWS Node, js React. JS Redux Workflow CI/CD

Ruby on Rails Developer, Tech Leader, Vinco Orbis

2016-11 — 2017-09

Ruby developer with Ruby on Rails Framework for education projects

- Lead a team of 2 people
- Teach to junior developers best practices
- Use TDD and CI/CD
- Use docker for create development environments

Lead Ruby on Rails Ruby CircleCi CI/CD TDD Rspec SCRUM

PHP Developer, Vinco

2015-04 — 2016-11

Orbis

PHP developer on Wordpress, Prestashop and vanilla PHP projects

- Create templates
- Paticipate in a team for international client

PHP Wordpress Prestashop

Software Developer, Coordinación General de Formación e Innovación Educativa (CGFIE), Instituto Politécnico Nacional (IPN)

2015-01 — 2015-12

I participated on numerous Vanilla PHP projects to teach to IPN community, I used git, gitlab, docker

- I worked on a local PHP MVC framework for standarized team workflow
- I installed a basic CentOS server for local use
- I proposed use the github workflow for developer team and created many manual for best development and deploy practices

PHP Linux MVC Codeigniter Git Gitlab Docker

Trainee Code, Feather México

2014-08 — 2015-01

Trainee developer, I participated on Ruby on Rails projects with PostgreSQL and Agile development techniques

- Participated on project for a big ensurance company
- I understood the MVC and Design Patterns

Agile Ruby Ruby on Rails PostgreSQL SCRUM HTML CSS MySQL PHP



Site Reliability Engineer,

2019-11 — Present

Exemplar

We need to analyze, plan and implement DevOps best practices such CI/CD, make pipelines and use Continuous deployment tools

Jenkins OKTA AWS GCP Docker Kubernetes Terraform Harness New Relic CI CD

API

Product for build interactive lessons for kids with multimedia resources from Youtube, Khan Academy Lite, Wikipedia, Red Magsiterial, Google Images

Education Ruby Docker Python Microservices Test Unit Rspec Continuous Integration Continuous Delivery API

Devops and backend developer, khan-lite-

2017-06

backend

Microservice for serve resources from Khan Academy Lite installation, build with ruby and docker containers Education Ruby Docker Microservices Ruby on Rails API

Devops and backend developer, wiki-

2017-06

download

Microservice for serve pdf from Wikipedia article, build with python and docker containers Education Docker Microservices Django Django Rest Framework API

Back-end developer, Grubertek API

2016-09 — 2017-04

RESTFUL API for Grubertek

PHP PHPUnit Vagrant Test Unit Continuous Integration Continuous Delivery API

Developer, SudoVerbs

2017-05

Bash console utility for learn english verbs

Bash Shell Education

Developer, tech lead, team lead, Royal Licoreria a

2017-09 — Present

Domicilio

Platform for deliver alcohol with hibrid and native mobile apps

React Native Redux Node MySQL Loopback App IOs Android

Developer, tech lead, team lead, Simulador Reto **ENARM**

2017-09 — Present

Simulator for ENARM test, this simulator helps to medics to study for ENARM test React Redux Node MySQL Loopback Node Docker Docker Compose

Developer, tech lead, team lead, Autounion

2017-09 — Present

This platform helps to agencies and customers to sell and find options for buy a car React Redux Node PostgreSQL Loopback Node Docker Compose Django

EDUCATION

BSCS, Universidad Autónoma del Estado de México

2010-06 — 2014-12

Branch on Software Development

EXTRACURRICULAR

CDMX, México 2017-03 — Present

CDMX

- Monthly speaker on docker meet
- Free Docker Courses organizer and speaker

Core Organizer, DevOpsDays Guadalajara Mexico 2020

Guadalajara, México 2020-03 — Present

CDMX, México 2019-12 — Present

CDMX, México 2020-03 — Present

- The First one event like this in Mexico
- Get sponsorships
- Made community events to get more exposure

Enchiladas DevOps Podcast, Co-

Host

- Make scripts for interviews
- Get guests to interview
- Make logo
- Edit and upload all episodes
- Get sponsorships
- Expose community events in social media
- Make community posts

Si no son enchiladas podcast,

Host

- Make scripts for interviews
- Make logo
- Edit and upload all episodes

WRITING

El porque las pruebas unitarias no sirven,

Medium

2017

La diferencia entre rake y rails,

Medium

2017

Un paso obligado para ser un desarrollador 'Pro,'

Medium

2017

** SPEAKING

ReactJS Basic

2017

Course,

• I teached to 10 people the first steps to ReactJS

Docker Basic Course, Docker Meetup Course

CDMX

• I spoke front of 100 people teaching the first steps to Docker technology